One of the key lessons that we have learned along
私たちが学んだ重要な教訓の１つは
the way is that it's important to think about machine learning serving,
機械学習の利用方法を考えることが 重要であるということです
about ML serving, not just about ML training.
機械学習ではトレーニングだけでなく 利用方法も考える必要があります
When you say machine learning to most people,
機械学習というと
they think about the complex pipeline on the left of this diagram.
多くの人はこの図の左側にある 複雑なパイプラインを考えます
It's certainly where you,
確かにデータエンジニアや データサイエンティストなら
will spend a lot of your time.
この部分に多くの時間を費やします
However, the key reason you're doing
しかし機械学習を行う重要な理由は
machine learning is on the right-hand side of this diagram.
この図の右側にあるのです
You want to serve out those predictions to decision makers
ノートブック、ダッシュボード、 アプリ、レポートを使って
using notebooks, dashboards, applications, reports.
意思決定者に役立つ予測を提供します
Operationalizing a machine learning model, by which we mean,
機械学習モデルの運用では
picking a model that's trained and
トレーニングされたモデルを選択し
getting to the point where he can serve out these predictions.
これらの予測を利用できるようにします
Operationalizing a machine learning model is hard,
機械学習モデルの運用は困難です
and many projects fail to make it to this prediction stage.
多くのプロジェクトが この予測の構築で失敗します
One of the lessons that we at Google
Googleが学んだ教訓があります
learned was that in order to reduce our chance of failure,
失敗の可能性を減らすには
we needed to make sure that we could process batch data and streaming data the same way.
バッチデータとストリーミングデータを 必ず同じ方法で処理するのです
Cloud Data Flow in this diagram,
この図のCloud Dataflowは
it's open source is Apache Beam.
オープンソースがApache Beamです
Cloud Data Flow helps us treat batch and stream the same way.
Cloud Dataflowによりバッチと ストリーミングを同じ方法で処理できます
So Cloud Data Flow is just one example of how, on Google Cloud,
Cloud DataflowはGoogle Cloudで
you get to take advantage of our experience,
機械学習のインフラストラクチャ構築に関する
Google's experience, in building machine learning infrastructure.
Googleの経験を利用する方法のほんの一例です
If you haven't taken our data engineering specialization on Coursera,
データエンジニアリングに関する Courseraの専門分野の受講がまだなら
I strongly encourage you to take it.
ぜひ受講してください
But in this track,
ただしここでは
we'll cover the key pieces as we go along.
重要なポイントを順番に取り上げます
Fortunately, for those of you data scientists out there,
幸運なことに データサイエンティストにとって
data engineering is not that hard to learn.
データエンジニアリングの習得は さほど難しくありません
On GCP, the key services are all serverless and they're all managed infrastructure.
GCPの主要サービスはすべてサーバーレスで 管理されたインフラストラクチャです
So in this course,
このコースでは
we will show you how to build batch and streaming data pipelines.
バッチとストリーミングの データパイプラインの構築方法を紹介します
By building your data pipelines on Google Cloud,
Google Cloudで データパイプラインを構築すれば
you essentially get to take advantage of the scalability,
機械学習システムを運用する際に